Noah Taiga Endo Software Engineer

M noah.taigameier@gmail.com

+81-80-7382-4853

Tokyo, Japan

German & Japanese citizenship

in www.linkedin.com/in/noah-taiga-endo

https://github.com/Octosub

ABOUT ME

With a background in **analytics** and professional experience in **customer service**, I bring a **rich cultural perspective** and adaptability from my **bilingual upbringing**. Recently graduating from **Le Wagon**'s web development boot camp, I'm proficient in **Ruby on Rails**, **React**, and familiar with **modern workflows** of the tech industry. Now I'm **highly motivated** to apply my skills in Tokyo's IT industry.

PROJECTS

CIET - Can I Eat This?

Lead Developer

An application for foreign vegans/vegetarians in Japan to scan food products and check if it meets their dietary restrictions.

//Ruby on Rails, Google API's, DeepL API, Stimulus JS, HTML, CSS, Stimulus JS, Heroku

Power UP!

A marketplace app where users can rent special powers from eachother. //Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Stimulus JS, Flatpickr, Devise

EDUCATION

01/2024 - 03/2024 Fullsta

Fullstack Web Development Bootcamp

Japan

LeWagon Tokyo 9-weeks **full-time intensive training** of the technical skills needed for a

successful career in tech, learning how to develop great products in teams using

modern workflows at the #1 web development bootcamp in the world.

2017 - 2022

Bachelor of Arts, Philosophy

Germany University of Konstanz

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

04/2020 - 10/2020

Mercedes-Benz Japan Co., Ltd.

Tokyo, Japan

Tokyo, Japan

Compliance Trainee

• Data protection for customers in accordance with the GDPR.

06/2022 – 12/2023

Guidepoint Japan

Research Associate

• Conducting **effective analysis** on various topics to consult clients in a **fast**

paced working environment

SKILLS

Backend

Frontend

Tools

Ruby on Rails, Webscraping & API's, ActiveRecord & SQL, CSV

HTML, CSS/SCSS, Javascript (Stimulus JS & React)

Git/Github, Heroku, Figma

LANGUAGES

lapanese

German

Enalish

Native/Bilingual proficiency

Native/Bilingual proficiency

Bilingual proficiency